

www.linkedin.com/in/alp-oran	in
alporan.github.io/blog	<u>_</u>
alporan@outlook.com	\searrow
+90-537 513 4529	<u>~</u>

PROFILE

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of developing, testing and maintaining software systems mainly using Java and related technologies. Quick adaptation to new challenges and responsibilities. Strong problem solving skills with an analytical mindset. Experience working as part of a productive team, as well as effectively self-manage during personal projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Şekerbank T.A.Ş.

Software Engineer, 2020-

Main responsibilities;

- Developing applications by using Java, Spring Framework, and Agile practices for the middleware utilized by digital banking channels (Web/Mobile Branches, Call Center, IVR, etc.)
- Taking part in architectural design of middleware layer as part of the microservices transformation.
- Maintaining legacy JSP-Servlet based Java EE web application.
- Bugfixing and troubleshooting.
- Carrying out Scrum related duties as Scrum Master.

BilgeAdam Technologies

Software Engineer, 2020-2021

Working as a Consultant Software Engineer at Şekerbank T.A.Ş.

Turkish Airlines

Software Engineer, 2017-2020

Main responsibilities;

- Developing mainframe applications for reservation, ticketing, and DCS systems using Java, Spring Framework, IBM High-Level Assembler, and Agile practices.
- Migrating mainframe applications to open systems as part of architectural transformation projects.
- Maintenance of codebase and database records.
- Bugfixing and troubleshooting.
- Automating manual tasks and test cases with Python Programming Language.
- Providing support for open system teams utilizing mainframe programs.
- Conducting code reviews.

EDUCATION

Sakarya University - Information Technologies

Turkey, Sakarya

Master of Science, 2018-2020

Istanbul Technical University - Electronics and Communications Engineering

Turkey, Istanbul *Bachelor of Science, 2011-2015*

PROJECTS

Gateway Application for Digital Channel Front-end Transformation

Backend For Frontend architecture implementation to address the needs of a new view layer developed with React. The implementation serves services of JSP/Servlet-based web application as RESTful APIs.

Personal Webpage/Blog

Static webpage for presenting my portfolio and blogging.

Tools: Jekyll, JavaScript, HTML, CSS **Link:** https://alporan.github.io/blog

Clinic Appointment Application

Implementing CRUD operations for simple clinic appointment application.

Tools: MySQL, Angular, Java, Spring Boot

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/clinic-appointment-app

Attachmate Extra! X-treme Macro Interface

Interface for developing utility programs and macros with Python programming language for Extra! X-treme terminals

Tools: Python, PyQt5, Extra! X-treme API

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/extra-xtreme-macro-interface

Blazing Fruits

Android game checks multitasking and hand-eye coordination.

Tools: Java, Android Studio, libGDX Library

Link: https://alporan.github.io/blog/blazing fruits

An Indoor Localization Algorithm On FPGA

Multiple RF reader modules were localized by using received signal strength value from stationary RFID tags. Localization algorithm was implemented on an FPGA.

Tools: Verilog, C++, FPGAs

Link: https://web.itu.edu.tr/~orssi/thesis/2015/AlpOran_bit.pdf

SKILLS

Programming Languages & Frameworks

- Java
- Spring Boot
- Spring MVC
- Spring Data JPA
- Hibernate
- Jakarta EE
- SQL
- IBM High-Level Assembler Language
- Python
- JUnit

Tools

- Git
- GitHub / BitBucket
- Relational Databases
- JIRA
- CA Endevor SCM
- CA Clarity PPM

LANGUAGES & TEST SCORES

Turkish: Native or bilingual proficiency **English**: Full professional proficiency

IELTS (International English Language Testing System), Nov 2015

Reading: 9/9, Listening: 8.5/9, Speaking: 7/9, Writing: 6/9

Overall Score: 7.5/9

TOEFL (Test Of English as a Foreign Language), Jul 2015

Reading: 26/30, Listening: 26/30, Speaking: 19/30, Writing: 21/30

Total Score: 92/120

┖